A Finding Aid to the Louis Pomerantz Papers, 1937-1988, bulk 1950s-1988, in the Archives of American Art aaa.pomeloui
Archives of American Art
- Photographic Material, 1940s-1980s; Series 9; 8.4 Linear feet Boxes 25-36, OV 37, MGP 1
  Travel slides document Pomerantz's travels to Israel where subjects include a museum visit, the Dead Sea, Damascus Gate, Independence Park, and Purim.
  Slide carousels contain slides used by Pomerantz in lectures and presentations, including presentations on the cleaning of a Robert Motherwell mural at the University of Iowa, and conservation of the George Sugarman sculpture Ramdam.
  "Slide notebooks" consist of slides documenting conservation techniques that were removed from unlabeled binders, transferred to archival housing in their original order and numbered sequentially according to their original binder groupings. Loose slides were removed from loose notebook slide pages and rehoused immediately after this group as they appeared to belong together.
  Project/client photographic material documents conservation treatment by project/client and is largely unsorted with the original boxes or labels preserved. Also found are large format X-rays and corresponding prints.
  Project/client negatives are 8 x 10s of paintings from collections belonging to individuals including Lou Block, Nathan Cummings, Epstein, and Arnold H. Maremont.
  Photographs and slides of artwork that do not appear to document specific damage or conservation work are housed at the end of the series.
  5 glass plate negatives are housed separately and are closed to researchers.
  - Artists, circa 1970s (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Pomerantz at Work, circa 1950s-1976 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    Includes 3 black and white prints and 2 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 1; other oversized material housed in Box 33, Folder 3
  - Pomerantz Family and Other Personal Negatives, circa 1950s (Box 25, Folder 20-21)
  - Travel Slides, circa 1970s (Box 25, Folder 22-24)
  - Conservation, University of Iowa, circa 1978 (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - Conservation, Robert Motherwell Mural, 1970s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 3-4)
  - Conservation Slides, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 5-9)
  - Negatives of Treatment, 1950s (Box 26, Folder 10-14)
  - Slide Carousels (Box 26)
    - Conservation Consideration for Artists, 1970s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Conservation of Chicago Board of Trade Ceres Mural, 1980s (Box 26, Folder 16-17)
    - Conservation of Sugarman Sculpture Ramdam (1963), 1985 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Fakes and Frauds, 1970s (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - For Art Students, Restretching Jack Levine's Witches Sabbath, circa 1970s (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Gamelan 1, Gamelan 2, circa 1970s (Box 26, Folder 21-22)
    - Repair Treatments and Treatments, 1980s (Box 26, Folder 23-24)
    - University of Illinois, Chicago, Materials and Methods for Prolonging the Life of Your Paintings, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - University of Illinois, Chicago, Problems with Twentieth Century Paintings, 1960s-1970s (Box 26, Folder 26-27)
    - University of Iowa, Museum of Art, Jackson Pollock Painting, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - University of Iowa, Museum of Art, Mounting of Motherwell Mural, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Slide Notebooks #1-2, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Slide Notebooks #2-5, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Slide Notebooks #5-7, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Slide Notebooks #6-7, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Slide Notebooks #7-10, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Slide Notebooks #10-12, circa 1970s (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Slide Notebooks #12-14, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Slide Notebook #14, and Loose Notebook Slides, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Loose Notebook Slides, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 3-4)
  - Project/Client Slides, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 28, Folder 5-8)
  - Project/Client Slides, Unsorted, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Project/Client Slides, Unsorted, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 29, Folder 1-10)
  - Project/Client Slides, Unsorted, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 30, Folder 1-11)
  - Project/Client Slides, Unsorted, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 31, Folder 1-9)
  - Project/Client Glass Slides and Glass Plate Negatives, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    2 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 1
  - Project/Client Negatives, circa 1950s (Box 32, Folder 3-11)
  - Project/Client Oversized Photos, circa 1960s-circa 1970s (Box 33, Folder 4-10)
  - Project/Client Oversized Photos, circa 1960s-circa 1970s (Box 34, Folder 1-4)
    Oversized material housed in OV 37
  - Artwork, French Landscapes, circa 1970s (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
  - Artwork, French Paintings, circa 1970s (Box 35, Folder 3-4)
  - Artwork, Miscellaneous, circa 1970s (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Artwork, Paintings, circa 1970s (Box 35, Folder 6-7)
  - Artwork, Pascin and Large Unsorted Photos, circa 1970s (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Artwork, Rembrandt, circa 1970s (Box 35, Folder 9-10)
  - Artwork, Unsorted, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Artwork Slides by Painter/Subject, circa 1970s (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Artwork Slides, Unsorted, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Pomerantz at Work from Box 25, Folder 19 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Glass Plate Negatives, 5 Glass negatives (Box MGP 1)
  - Oversized Project/Client Oversized Photos from Box 34 (Box OV 37)